bench.co 2014-10-23

# Bench — Privacy Policy

##### In a nutshell

We take privacy and data security seriously. We are committed to being fair and transparent in the collection and use of your data. The Privacy Policy below describes how we protect you and how we use your data to provide you with our services.

##### Summary

We capture, manage and store data that may include your Personal Information as part of our normal operations and service offerings. This Privacy Policy describes why we capture, how we use and the circumstances under which we may disclose this information.

By visiting or registering on our site, or by using our service, regardless of the manner or device made available and supported by us through which you choose to do so, you are agreeing to our Privacy Policy, outlined below. We assume certain responsibilities and make related commitments to you. We also clarify that we are not liable with respect to misuse of the site by you or others and other third party risks beyond our control that may affect your Personal Information.

If you have concerns about this, you should contact us at [privacy@bench.co](mailto:privacy@bench.co).

> **by using our site or services, you agree to the terms of this privacy policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your personal information according to this privacy policy. your personal information may be processed by us or on our behalf in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the united states) where laws regarding processing of personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.**

##### What is personal information?

Personal Information includes your name, mailing address, phone number, e-mail address and demographic and other personally identifiable information about you as an individual. If you are a user of our site, it will also include business information that you contribute which concerns business and personal relationships between yourself and other individuals and organizations (“Bookkeeping Data”). You may provide or upload Personal Information in order to enable us to provide you with our services. We may also ask for certain Personal Information when you request information about or order our products and services, participate in our marketing, sales or other promotional activities, or correspond with us. If you are in a part of our site that requires you to provide your Personal Information, it will be clear what Personal Information we are requesting.

##### Why do we collect your information?

We collect, use and disclose information that can identify you (“Personal Information”) so that we can:

  * establish your identity;
  * provide to you the services offered by the Site and bill any amounts due from you;
  * troubleshoot and resolve problems;
  * improve the usability, performance and effectiveness of our Site and business;
  * provide you with news, updates, and reminders related to our services;
  * enforce our Terms of Service;
  * protect you and us from error and fraud;
  * understand your needs and eligibility for products and services;
  * comply with legal and regulatory requirements;
  * and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

We only collect Personal Information that we consider necessary for achieving these purposes.

We may also collect, process, store and analyze anonymous information about you obtained from your browser or through the use of “cookies” or other tools that track, measure and analyze the behaviors and usage patterns of visitors to our site and users of our services. We may use third party tracking services to track and analyze such anonymous information from users of our service, and such third parties may use cookies to help track user behavior.

We may send you communications via email about our service. You can opt out of receiving communications from us by changing your notification settings on our website. Please note that even if you unsubscribe or opt-out, we may still send you urgent service related communications (e.g., if your credit card payment was declined). If you do not wish to receive them, you must delete your account with us.

##### Who do we share your personal information with?

Except as set forth in this privacy policy, we do not sell or release your Personal information to third parties without your consent. However, we reserve the right to gather, analyze, aggregate and transform non-personally identifiable information sourced from all or any portion of our visitors and users, and to make this information available at our site or through other means, channels or partners at such time and on such terms as we believe are appropriate.

We retain the right to manage our operations, including using service providers of our own choosing, to facilitate the development, hosting and ongoing support of our services to meet our business goals. For example, we may use the services of third-party companies to host our services and these services may or may not be located in the same jurisdictions or regions as the customers using our services. Our employees, consultants, contractors, suppliers and partners, if authorized, may have access to our customer information or the systems storing it as part of and solely for the purposes of performing their jobs, or within the scope of their agreements with us. In all cases, we use reasonable efforts to ensure that your Personal Information, as part of our confidential business information, is protected under contracts with such persons.

Some of our service providers include:

  * Amazon Web Services (web hosting)
  * FedEx (shipment of documents)
  * Shoeboxed.com (scanning of documents)

While we take care to use only service providers that we believe are reputable and able to live up to our and your expectations, including about the handling of confidential information, Bench is not liable for unlawful or unauthorized use of Personal Information by any of such persons unless such unlawful use was a direct result of our gross negligence or wilful misconduct.

With your authorization, we may disclose your Bookkeeping Data (and any Personal Information related thereto) through our service to a third party accountant or other services of yours. If you authorize this disclosure, the use and disclosure restrictions contained in this Privacy Policy will not apply to such third party. We do not control the privacy practices of any third parties. We do not currently have any Affiliates, but if we do in the future, we may disclose your Personal Information to a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, **“Affiliates”** ), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. In addition, if another company merges with us, acquires us, or purchases our assets, including in bankruptcy, we may provide your Personal Information to such third party, in which case such company may continue to process your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

We will also share your Personal Information if we are required by law (including any generally applicable law or any specific court order or other legal process binding on us) or if we otherwise determine in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to resolve disputes and/or protect or defend the rights or property of Bench and other users. We will use reasonable efforts to make you aware of such disclosure promptly unless we are prevented from doing so.

If you provide feedback to us, we may use and disclose such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate such feedback with your Personal Information. We will collect any information contained in such feedback and will treat the Personal Information in it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

##### Your use of the personal information of others

If you choose to provide Personal Information of any third party, we will assume that you have the third party’s permission to provide us that information. Examples include Site referrals to friends. This information will not be used for any purposes other than those described above. You agree that, with respect to the Personal Information of other persons that you collect, use and disclose on the Site, you have all necessary consents and rights to collect, use and disclose that information as described in this Privacy Policy from time to time, and you agree that the indemnity you give to us in the Terms of Service applies to any non-compliance by you with respect to the foregoing.

The site may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. When you click on such a link, you will leave our service and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Information from you, and we do not collect information from you that you submit on such third party sites.

##### What is our security policy?

We use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that Personal Information is secure, including https protocol and encryption. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect, as well as the modes of access to it. While we strive to protect your Personal Information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. More information about security is available in our Terms of Service.

##### How can you access, correct and update your personal information?

Much of your Personal Information is available to you through your account. To review and update your Personal Information to ensure it is accurate, you may login into your account to make the changes, or you may contact us. If we are unable to provide access or disclose information to you, we will explain why, subject to any legal or regulatory restrictions.

##### How can you delete your account?

All Personal Information linked to your account will be deleted at your request as soon as reasonably possible in accordance with the law. When you make a request to delete your account, your data will be deleted from our production servers, and you will no longer be able to access your account. However, we may retain your Personal Information to comply with laws, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our terms of service, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

Please remember, however, if we have already disclosed some of your Personal Information to third parties, such as your accountant, we cannot access that Personal Information any longer and cannot force the deletion or modification of any such information by the parties to whom we have made those disclosures.

Aggregated or anonymous data derived from your Personal Information, which cannot be traced back to your account, may remain on our production servers indefinitely. We reserve the right to use any aggregated or anonymous data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information.

##### How will you learn of updates to our privacy rules?

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our privacy and data management practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Our service is not directed to children and children are not eligible to use it. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. We do not collect or maintain Personal Information from people we actually know are under 13 years of age, and no part of our service is designed to attract people under 13 years of age. If we later learn that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user's Personal Information from our databases and to prevent the user from utilizing the service.

##### Who should you contact with comments and questions?

Bench welcomes your comments and questions regarding this Privacy Policy and the use of your Personal Information. If you have questions, concerns or if you would like more detailed information please email our privacy officer at [privacy@bench.co](mailto:privacy@bench.co).
